The hard part isn't always making money,
it's knowing what to do with it and how
to keep it. Most financial advice tells
you what not to buy and what assets to
invest in. [music] I am going to do that
in this video, but I'm also going to
tell you the 10 things that you should
actually upgrade today. [music]
Because if you make more money, you
should be able to enjoy it and also
sometimes spending it makes you [music]
even more. And number three is the one
almost nobody spends on and I will never
go back. But, there is one thing we need
to get straight first. Before you buy
anything that feels like a lifestyle
upgrade, ask one question. Does this buy
back my life or does it try to make me
look richer without a reason? To answer
that, you need what I call your buyback
rate. If I can actually pay someone less
than half of what my hour is worth to
take a task off my plate, I usually
should. Here's why. If you take your net
income and you divide it by the total
number of hours worked, there are about
2,000 or so working hours in a year,
which will give you your hourly income.
[music]
Now, I want you to take that and divide
it by two. That's how you get your your
50% margin. Any task you can give to
somebody else under that number is a
let's go. So, let's say you make
$100,000. If we have 100k, what are we
going to do? Your hourly rate is about
50 bucks, which means if we cut it in
half, your buyback rate is $25.
[music] So, if you can pay somebody
anything less, 10 bucks an hour, then
you really should do that. So, this is
the first thing you should upgrade.
Spend more on the things that make you
more money.
A lot of people say upgrade your
wardrobe, get fancier. I actually don't
buy into all of that at all. I think you
need one expensive [music]
as
thing to wear consistently. Why? You're
signaling rich, especially if you do
things like sell real estate or try to
get people to invest in your company or
even try to show your boss that you want
to get promoted. I like having one super
nice purse that I wear with [music]
every outfit. Um, Um, this one's called
Schiaparelli. Uh, it's an expensive
brand, But the moral story is you don't
need a ton of these, you need one. If
you're a dude, you need one nice watch.
It could be fake. Nobody needs to know.
Not only that, [music] if we have the
rule of one, which is spend money on one
nice thing because it'll actually make
you more [music] money,
I think the next thing you got to do is
the rule of three. Right now, get rid of
three things in your closet that don't
fit anymore [music]
and are kind of gnarly and replace them.
That way you're pulling in the wealthy
things and getting rid of the things
that actually keep you looking [music]
like you don't belong at this level of
the game. I like doing this on a weekly
basis. If I'm going to bring anything
new, I usually get rid of something
else. I think there's just like human
psychology to that [music] winning.
Next I want to talk to you about why I
made a million dollars before I was 30
and one of my smarter, better coworkers
didn't. It's actually one word [music]
and the word is proximity. If you want
to get rich fast, you actually want to
pay to have time back in your day
because you are not commuting far. Why?
When I was at Goldman Sachs back in the
day, I had to be in the office at 7:30
every single day. I had a two-minute
walk from my office to Goldman Sachs. My
best colleague, smarter than me, better
than me, better pedigree, better at
Excel, well, he had to be in the office
at 7:30 as well. Like he hadn't saved as
much money as I had, so he had to be 45
minutes from the office. He missed every
single morning where I got there before
him. He missed all the times that he
left and couldn't come back where I
could. Proximity will make you more
money. In this case, it might be
actually the better gym where the
classes are full of people that you
might actually meet somebody who wants
to invest in your business, wants to
hire you, whatever. My friend Sahil
Bloom became very close with the former
head of Apple for that exact reason. I
also think joining a co-working space
instead of your kitchen table. It costs
you money not to be in the room with
other winners. I think I joined three or
four masterminds before I made all my
cash because you're paying for who else
paid to be in the exact same room and
stealing their 10,000 hours. This isn't
just me, a Harvard economist studied
millions of people and he basically
mapped billions of friendships using
Facebook data. You know what's crazy if
you think about it like this, the single
strongest predictor of whether someone
climbs out of their economic bracket
wasn't their school, their neighborhood
or their income. In fact, if you thought
about the clusters of what happened, it
was actually who did they know that had
a lot of money. It was whether their
social circle actually touched people
not just at their same socioeconomic
level, but did they climb a rung and
another rung and another rung. What's
the translation here? Your network is a
measurable input to your income. You
know that saying like your network is
your net worth, it turns out that the
data actually shows this is true. It's a
lot easier to change your environment
that it is to change your habits, so I
would start here. Actually, I have
something for you. Knowing how valuable
proximity can be, I'm going to do
something I've never done before. I'm
putting together one of the largest
events ever for owners on September
18th. It's completely free. I'm giving
away millions of dollars of prizes and
you get to be online with owners looking
to scale their businesses live. You can
sign up here in the description. Like I
said, completely free. I'm going to
teach you everything I know about
building profitable businesses. This is
how you change your life.
Research shows that how you take care of
yourself and your presentation actually
makes you more money. People who are
rated as attractive actually earned,
this shocked me, 20% more on average. So
the way you look matters. I [music]
think like don't hate the player, don't
hate the game. Ridiculously expensive
beauty things I do that are actually
worth it. I'll start high then we'll go
low. First, like this is for chicks but
you can get it for your girl. Uh PRP,
this is like where they micro needle
your own blood or now they actually
micro needle um crazy things in your
face like salmon semen and other stuff.
So I think that's probably like 5K
depending on what level, if you do
peptides inside of it. Next, something
called Halo. That's like 3 to 5K, super
intense lasers that laser your face, but
genuinely make you look 5 years younger.
Then, stuff like Sculptra. This
basically [music] pulls back your face,
kind of like fill in collagen. I'm not a
doctor, I don't know. I'm just telling
you the stuff I do to try to not look
40. Sculptra's going to run you a couple
K. And then, like a facial, which is
basically on the cheaper side, that's
going to be a couple hundred. But, maybe
the really inexpensive things that I do.
You can get these red lights that are
amazing for your face. This one
literally sits on my desk every day.
I also have one that I lay down with.
Because most of what actually works
isn't expensive [music]
at all. Like, I use the red lights. I
highly recommend that. I use a lot of
organic [music] products, like OSEA. I
really like their stuff and all their
oils. Pretty much across the board, as
much organic makeup as you can. Now, for
dudes, you can actually these days do
all these same [music] things that
Chicks do. And I think it's actually an
underrated hack for men to look hotter.
Don't look weird, though. Don't do like
shiny, don't do fillers, don't get
crazy. Unless you're going for the
RuPaul look, and then, you know, good
for you.
Most people at this point say that you
should have a financial advisor. I
actually [music] say no. I think you
should have a tax advisor. So, once
you've made, in my opinion, at least a
couple hundred K a year, you're [music]
probably overpaying in taxes, and
especially if you're an employee, you
need to figure out a way for the IRS to
take less from you, legally. Cuz nobody
looks good in orange. What's the
difference between a tax advisor and a
financial advisor? A financial advisor,
well, they get paid differently. They
usually take a percentage cut on every
single dollar they have sitting with
them that you go and invest with them. I
don't actually [music] love that. If I
was you, I would just put it in a van If
I was me, I won't tell you what to do.
I'd just put it in a Vanguard or a
Fidelity, some sort of cheap structure,
dollar cost averaged, continue [music]
to invest over the long time, allow it
to compound. But, that doesn't help you
at all with your earned income. So, a
tax advisor will actually tell you,
"Okay, um why don't we structure this
LLC, have these earnings go through it
[music] so that we can use that to
decrease your actual cost basis, the
amount of money that you give to the IRS
each year." Tax sounds fancy, but it's
actually [music] just the way that most
people stay rich. People actually have a
fund for getting into things, like a
down payment fund and start the business
fund. Almost nobody has a fund for
getting out of it. This is important
because the [music] exit is almost
always more expensive than the entry.
And it's the one cost nobody budgets for
until they're already trapped and paying
it in a panic. For the exit fund, this
is a separate account whose only job is
buying your way out. [music] This is how
you break your lease. You eat a
cancellation fee. You pay a kill fee to
walk away from a client or vendor that's
quietly draining you. You don't touch it
for anything else. Why? The truth is,
most of us are too scared of the exit
cost to admit things aren't working out.
So, we just stay and pay a slower,
quieter price instead. Before you commit
to anything, price out exactly what it
cost to undo it, not just what it cost
to start it. So, before you sign that
lease, that contract, or that 12-month
vendor agreement, ask what walking away
costs in month six. Put that number
aside before you sign. Some of the most
disciplined companies on Earth, they're
going to pay people to quit on purpose,
which is wild. Like Amazon offers
warehouse employees an actual cash
payment to leave. [music] In Jeff's own
words, the goal is making people stop
and think about what they really want
because an employee who stays somewhere
they don't want to be, that's not
healthy for you or the business. If a
big company is willing to pay five
figures just to buy back the option of a
clean exit, that tells you something
about what staying trapped [music] costs
you. So, before the end of the day,
write a list of your three to five
expenses you want [music] to kill. Name
it something that keeps you honest. I
like exit fund. I also like the you
fund, meaning [music] you can walk out
at any point if you don't like them and
say, "You know what?" Every time you
sign something recurring, basically add
its kill fee to [music] the total you're
saving towards.
So, I want to talk about the food. I
don't think clean eating is just like a
signal. This stuff really matters. Like
actual food, the stuff a plant or an
animal would recognize prepared by a
human instead of a drive-thru window.
There's so many studies on this, you
guys. Young adults and older adults show
the same pattern. Every meaningful
increase in ultra-processed food tracks
to worse memory and concentration. You
cannot make a ton of money, negotiate a
deal, or show up for your kids' game,
right, on a brain that's been running on
gas station calories all day forever.
There's a bunch of studies that also
show people spend an average of 7 hours
a week cooking. So, I don't know. Like
maybe use a healthy meal prep service. I
use one. It gets delivered to your door
every week. You can skip the expensive
shopping trip. Like also interesting,
there are all these prepared food
companies like Factor Meals or Tempo.
They're like 200, 300 bucks a week for
21 meals. So, for some people, this is a
no-brainer. Others, the buyback rate
doesn't work out. Do the math, see what
works for you. We have a chef that cooks
for us. It costs about $60 an hour, and
in about 3 hours, they can cook enough
food for us for 3 days. [music] So,
actually, when you look at that cost,
it's sort of a no-brainer. People assume
eating well
>> [music]
>> is really expensive automatically. And
two fast food meals a day for a
household actually adds up faster than a
grocery run. For the end of the day,
what's your one action? Throw out that
old stuff that's in your desk drawer
that you probably shouldn't be eating
anyway, and restock it with something
that's going to go bad if you don't eat
it today.
This is really unpopular advice. I will
not invest in a founder unless they
already have an assistant. People hate
this advice, but I got to give it to me
by a billionaire. And when I saw the
data, I was actually like pretty shocked
on this. Harvard Business found that
execs who work with a skilled assistant
have [music] 20 to 30% higher
productivity and make more money. A good
assistant actually doesn't cost you
money in the long term, they make you
money because of all the hours you waste
on your own admin previously. Okay, I
have two things I want you to tattoo on
your forehead if you want to make more
money. First is what's called Kato. I
think I originally stole this from Tim
Ferriss and I might have updated it
slightly myself. What does this mean?
Cut, automate, delegate, outsource. So,
what I do first is I obsess on all the
things that I should not do. Obviously
Netflix and chill, but other things like
do I really need to be organizing my
email [music] list? Like should I just
not do that? So, those are my kill
items. Second, automate. Hey, I have to
read email. Okay, well, can I use
something like Superhuman, which is the
software I use, that automates all of my
email inbox management better? Great.
Okay, if Superhuman isn't sufficient,
this is when I bring in usually a
virtual assistant. They can cost you
like a couple hundred bucks to a couple
thousand bucks a month and they will
actually do anything that you want to
delegate. And fully outsourcing might
mean hiring an EA or another member of
your team to do this job entirely.
They're not even reporting back to you,
they're just executing [music] on it.
You start with the lowest level tasks
from a dollar perspective and you climb
to the highest level tasks from a dollar
perspective. Now, let's say that you're
listening to me and you're like, "Cody,
I want to make more money and I need
more time to focus on selling things."
Let me show you how to scale up the
assistant [music] ladder. The assistant
ladder essentially has three rungs on
it. Rung one is a virtual assistant.
This is part-time, overseas, cheap. You
can basically get this for 200 bucks to
3,000 bucks a month. 3,000 is full-time,
by the way. You use this for any inbox
scheduling, repetitive tasks. This
clears the buyback rate for almost
everybody watching. Rung two is actually
an assistant. This person is in-house,
more trustworthy. They could still be
remote, but they know more about you.
And they can be used to filter out
unimportant daily life tasks. Then,
we've got the chief of staff. This runs
projects end-to-end, makes the calls
you'd make, walks into a room and can
actually brief them on it say, "Cody's
not going to like that. Cody is going to
like this." You know, this I like to
train them up to be my duplicate. This
is the top of the ladder. Most of you
aren't there yet, but you don't know
where you're going to go unless you
start here. So, let's say this one costs
2,000 to 3,000. Let's say this one costs
50,000 a year, all the way up to
$250,000
a year. And let's say a chief of staff
probably costs somewhere around 125k.
These people can earn a lot. They can
earn
>> [music]
>> 300k a year being a chief of staff. This
is really important because you need to
let go of the 10 hours you're
white-knuckling because it's faster if
you just do it. That line, "It's faster
if you just do it," is probably why you
you're not where you want to be at
monetarily. And it's usually why most
people stay broke. Yeah, everybody's
faster once. I'm 100 times faster than
most of my employees. But you're not
faster the 51st time. So, the upgrade
here is more free time doing the things
that make you more money. My action for
you is pretty simple. Before the end of
the day, write down the three tasks
eating your week that don't require you
specifically using Cato. [music]
That list is your job for getting to
rung one.
All right, the next one I want to talk
about is sleep. So, this economist
actually found that [music] the more
sleep you have, it's associated with
higher earnings. And that kind of makes
sense, right? Because tired people make
expensive decisions. So, so like if you
really zoom out, chronic short-term
sleep costs the US [music] economy $411
wild. It's basically a giant liability.
[music] So, what do I do to improve my
sleep? Really, really simple. One,
a hard mattress. There's a lot [music]
of studies that show these are better.
And not like an old mattress and if you
have an old mattress [music]
you really need to replace it every 5 to
10 years. Two, I hyper believe in this
one but it is expensive, Eight Sleep. I
got a discount code for you guys. You
can click the link below. I don't even
think I make money on this anymore.
[music] So, you guys just take the 600
bucks or whatever it is off this. This
has been a game changer for my sleep.
You want to go way cheaper than this?
Earplugs and a face [music] mask. This
is the whole list. Like you don't need
an Oura Ring. You don't need a Whoop.
You don't need sleep tracking. You don't
really need the Eight Sleep. It's just
sick if you have the couple thousand
bucks to spend on it. So, let's run the
buyback rate on this. If Eight Sleep is
about 5K
>> [music]
>> for instance to get the whole thing plus
like de minimus
like let's call it like a hundred bucks
for everything else that I just
mentioned, the face mask, [music] the
earplugs, maybe a little bit better of a
pillow. What are you looking at? At 2500
hours a year, that's [music] like a $2
buyback rate. So, that's kind of a
no-brainer if you have ever under slept
and that decision has cost you in a
negotiation, in your business or in your
life. Next I want to think about what?
And my favorite thing to upgrade is
always Y O U but I have a really
particular way to do it. I call this the
repeat rule.
And here's how I like to think about it.
How many times if you acquire this skill
will you repeat its use? So, if it's
sales, that's probably a thousand times.
It's going to keep showing up in your
paycheck. If it's negotiation, that's
probably at least a hundred times. So,
the higher the number of times you're
going to repeat it, the more you're
going to want it. Sometimes I also think
about something called the tattoo rule.
Like if I could take this skill, tattoo
it on my body so it or my brain so I
would never forget it, would I rather
have that or the money back to learn it?
Pretty quickly you're going to realize
the things that you'd use again and
again and again you wish that you could
tattoo on your brain and that's when you
decide the skills that stick. My most
important skills ever?
Negotiation. That's why I obsess on
people learning how to buy businesses.
Sales, because CEO is chief sales
officer. Operations and processes.
That's why we actually run an entire
event learning how to run a business.
Because even if you're the best
salesperson, if you don't understand
profitability, you're going to go out of
business, which is actually what we're
teaching live at our event on September
18th. It will be every single step I've
used to buy a business. I can promise
you, if you learn the game of business,
which is really the game of money, it's
really hard to go broke.
The most important thing to upgrade
going forward, we've talked about it
before,
is your time. I want you to think about
the most unhinged things you could do
right now to buy back your time. For me,
that's like my nail lady comes to my
office every single time I get it done.
I never go to the nail salon. By the
way, so does my hair and makeup artist.
So does the person who even dyes my hair
comes into the office. So does [music]
my stylist who brings me clothes. Oh, by
the way, so does my chef who drops off
my food here. I know I sound like a
really high-maintenance broad, but how
else do you build a nine-figure company
plus have a husband that you love and
hang out with plus be pregnant plus like
want to have friends and family and
travel around. Like this is where I buy
back all my time from all the nonsense.
And I swear to God, you guys, somebody
is going to tell you this is so dumb.
Must be nice. And I'm going to tell you
that's why that person will never be as
successful as you want to be. I know a
lot of [music] people don't like to hear
this, but you are the biggest reason why
you aren't successful and it is
typically because you are not valuing
your time properly. [music] And the
second you break through that and you
get out of your head what I used to
think too, which is this is so elitist
having all this stuff. Like this is kind
of gross buying all of that. Can't you
do anything for yourself? It's like the
fire movement infected our brains and
made us think [music] that in order to
have a good life, we had to be minimal
and be in the fire movement and save
every penny. No, no, guys, the world's
hugely abundant. There's more money and
opportunity [music] and wealth than you
can ever imagine out here. And the best
thing is,
at a certain point it doesn't have to
cost you more [music] time to do it all.
In fact, you can work less, have more
fun, [music] and make more once you
learn this thing that only rich people
do.